▍2026 美网 女单1/4决赛
莱巴金娜 3-6 6-1 6-4 郑钦文 · 赛后新闻发布会
Questions?
有记者提问吗？
Cole.
请这位记者提问。
Hey there, sorry about the loss,
很遗憾你今天输掉了比赛，
but it's been a remarkable run
但这次征程非常出色，
from qualifiers to the quarter final.
从资格赛一路打进八强。
Just can you kind of reflect
能否请你回顾一下？
upon just how maybe,
从当时到现在，
I know it's a little bit tough to think
我知道刚输球，
about now, but how proud are you
很难去想，但你有多自豪？
of the run, given that big reset you
从在佛罗里达重新调整，
had in Florida to where you are now?
然后才一路走到了今天。
I think the win that I had so far for sure
我认为此前取得的那些胜利，
is great, but obviously today in the match,
当然很棒。但今天这场比赛，
I had got a lot of chance in the third set,
我在决胜盘有很多机会，
but I didn't took it.
却没有把握住。
It was a bit pity for me to lose this match,
输掉这场比赛，有些遗憾。
but obviously I could take positive things
但我也能从中有所收获，
from U.S.
从今年这次美网之旅中，
Open this year.
带走这些收获。
Despite the loss,
虽然今天输了，
what do you think was the key today
你觉得今天的关键是什么？
to what you could have done to win?
怎样做，才有机会赢？
What do you think you could have done?
你觉得自己还能做些什么？
Well, obviously I think that passing shot I
我觉得，那个穿越球，
missed makes some difference.
没打进，确实影响了结果。
And of course, I think maybe
当然，我也觉得，
when she serves second serve,
面对她的二发时，
I could be more aggressive sometimes
有些时候我可以更主动，
and make a bit less mistake in the return
接发球也能再少些失误。
because when the rally gets long,
因为回合一旦拉长，
I think it's where I get more points.
我觉得自己就更容易得分。
So I mean, today's just few points makes
所以，今天就是几个关键分，
a difference and that's it.
决定了胜负。就是这样。
I have nothing to say.
没有更多想说的了。
Congratulations on a nice run, Qinwen.
钦文，祝贺你这次的表现。
How does your mindset, as you,
想问一下你的心态。
I know it's right after the match,
我知道比赛才刚结束，
but looking towards the end of the year,
但展望今年接下来的赛程，
the rest of the tournaments to play,
还有那些待打的比赛，
how different does your
你的心态有多大变化？
mindset feel now maybe compared
现在的感受，
to earlier this year in spring when you were
比起今年春天，当时你觉得，
feeling like you couldn't get any rhythm
自己始终找不到节奏，
or really have a chance to fight in matches?
也很难在比赛中展开争夺。
I think the good thing is I know how
好的一点是，现在我知道，
to compete better
怎样更好地投入竞争，
than before, than in the beginning
比此前、比年初，
of the year.
都做得更好了。
In the beginning of the year,
年初的时候，
I was a bit totally out of tournament,
我有点完全脱离了比赛状态，
like rhythm.
找不到比赛节奏。
And obviously this tournament helps me
这次赛事显然帮助了我，
to find myself little by little.
让我一点点找回自己。
And in the match just today,
至于今天这场比赛，
I think there's a lot to learn when I lost
输了，也有很多值得学习。
because there are some decisions
因为有些决策，
in the important moment.
是在关键时刻做出的，
I wasn't doing right.
而我当时没有做好。
And that was also a very physical match
这场比赛对体能的要求，
for me.
对我来说也很高。
She got a great serve
她的发球很出色，
and I think I have to be really focused
所以我必须高度集中，
to return every single time.
认真应对每一次接发球。
In general,
总的来说，
I could take some positive things
我能带走一些积极的收获。
and the rest I could go back
其余的，我可以回去总结，
and to do what I can do better.
看看哪些地方能做得更好。
Congratulations on your run.
祝贺你这次的表现。
What will you carry forward expanding
接着刚才问的，哪些收获，
on Eva's question throughout the rest
你会带到接下来的比赛中，
of the year and the next year,
延续到今年余下赛季和明年？
especially having
尤其是经历了，
these great comeback wins
这些精彩的逆转，
and those 5–0 down sets?
包括盘中0比5落后后的翻盘。
I think tennis also gives me a lesson all
我觉得，网球一直在教会我，
the time that as soon as the match
只要比赛，
is not over, you just have to keep fighting
还没有结束，就要继续战斗。
because you never know what can happen
因为你不知道会发生什么，
in one tennis game.
网球比赛里，一切皆有可能。
And second things is I think there's
第二点是，我觉得自己，
so much more.
还有很多、很多，
I still have on myself to improve.
可以提升的地方。
So that's the positive things.
这也是积极的一面。
And yeah, no more I can say.
没有更多要说的了。
We know how you're different tennis -wise
我们知道，你在网球方面，
from a year or two years ago.
和一两年前已经有所不同。
How are you different personality -wise?
那你的性格发生了哪些变化？
Well, I would say deep inside me,
我想说，在内心深处，
I haven't changed that much.
我并没有改变太多。
The things is after an injury
只是受伤之后，
because I'm not doing so well.
因为自己的表现不太好，
So I try to learn like a bit,
所以我试着学着，
hide a bit my character to don't show
把自己的个性稍微收起来，
that much because you know
不要展露太多。你也知道，
when you don't have a good result,
当你没有好成绩的时候，
people just judge you.
人们就会评判你。
But I'm just the same person.
但我还是同一个人。
It doesn't matter if I win or if I lost.
无论赢球还是输球，
I think the same.
我的想法都一样。
I think it's important to be a good person
我认为，做一个好人很重要，
and then stay humble in life.
在生活中保持谦逊也很重要。
But sometimes people just don't like
但有时，人们就是不喜欢，
when you speak the reality
你说实话。
and when you like,
有时候，
they like more when you speak fake stuff
他们反而更喜欢听假话。
but that's not how I am.
可我不是那样的人。
I would say I become better.
我想说，我变得更好了。
I'm more open compared to two,
我现在更开放了，相比于，
three years ago
两三年前的自己。
but the base has never changed.
但根本的东西从未改变。
I'm still myself, yeah.
我还是我自己。对。
That's true.
是这样。
Congratulations.
祝贺你。
You'll get a chance to probably play
接下来你应该有机会，
at home in the next few months
在未来几个月回到主场比赛。
and just how relieved maybe excited
你有多安心，又有多兴奋？
are you
对于这个机会，
to have that opportunity now having taken
能带着这次比赛的势头，
this momentum from this tournament,
回到主场，
hopefully into the fall?
并希望延续到秋季赛程？
I always, I'm so excited to play in China
我一直很期待在中国比赛。
especially coming from qualifying US Open
尤其从美网资格赛出发，
and then reach until here
然后一路打到这里。
that was a really, really difficult journey
这段旅程非常、非常艰难，
for me.
对我来说确实如此。
Of course, playing at home always,
当然，回到主场比赛，
I'm more motivated and also
我总会更有动力，
in the same time, carry out some pressure
同时也会承受一些压力，
because I really wants to do it well there
因为我真的很想在那里打好。
but I just want to say, keep calm
但我想对自己说：保持冷静，
and just training day by day, focus
一天一天地训练，专注，
in the match by match, focus on the present
一场一场地打，专注当下。
because when your mind's trying
因为当你的思绪，
to go everywhere, thinking too much,
到处飘、想得太多时，
that's not helping for tennis.
对打网球是没有帮助的。
Last question. That was my question.
最后一问。那就是我的问题。
That was your question.
那就是你的问题。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
Thank you.
谢谢。